A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Urban Poverty Program, Office Files of Anne C. Kubisch, Prudence Brown and Janice Molnar FA666
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Urban Poverty Program, Office Files of Anne C. Kubisch, Prudence Brown and Janice Molnar
1984-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Brown, Prudence
Molnar, Janice Marie, 1954-
Kubisch, Anne C.
Ford Foundation
FA666
5.24 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged in 2 series by file type.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Chronological Correspondence Files, 1992-1996
Series II. Subject Files, 1984-1995
Conditions Governing Access
Records are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains correspondence and subject files.
Biographical / Historical
Prudence Brown is a community development and philanthropy consultant who worked for over ten years at the Ford Foundation. Brown started at the Ford Foundation as a Program Officer in the Division of National Affairs. After a change in the Foundation's program structure, Brown became a Program Officer in the United States and International Affairs Programs (USIAP), Urban Poverty Program. She then took on leadership positions in the larger USIAP as Officer in Charge and then Director. Following another change in the Foundation's program structure, Brown became Deputy Director of the Urban Poverty Program.
After leaving the Ford Foundation in 1992, Brown became a Research Fellow at Chaplin Hall at the University of Chicago. In 2008, she became an independent consultant.
Brown earned a B.A. in psychology from the University of Chicago in 1970 and a M.S.W. and Ph.D. in social work and psychology from the University of Michigan in 1976. Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, she worked as an Assistant Professor in the School of Social work at Columbia University.
Biographical / Historical
Anne C. Kubisch is a foundation executive who worked for several years at the Ford Foundation. In 1985, she joined the Foundation as an Assistant Program Officer in the Developing Country Programs. She then moved from the larger Developing Country Programs to its specific West Africa Program as Assistant Representative and Program Officer. Later, she moved to the Urban Poverty Program where she worked as a Program Officer before being appointed Deputy Director.
After leaving the Ford Foundation in 1994, Kubisch became Director for the Roundtable on Community Change at The Aspen Institute. In 2003, she became President and CEO of the Ford Family Foundation (TFFF).
Kubisch earned a B.A. in English from Tufts University and a master's degree in public policy from the Princeton University School of Public and International Affairs. Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, she worked as a Staff Assistant to David Rockefeller.
Biographical / Historical
Janice Molnar is a state government official who worked for several years at the Ford Foundation during the 1990s. Molnar started at the Ford Foundation as a Program Officer in the Urban Poverty Program before being promoted to Deputy Director. Following a change in the Foundation's program structure, she became Co-acting Deputy Director of the Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health unit (HDRH).
Molnar's career in civil service includes her time as Deputy Commissioner for Program Operations for the New York City Department of Youth and Community Development. In 2007, she was appointed Deputy Commissioner for the New York State Office of Children and Family Services (OCFS) Division of Child Care Services.
Molnar earned a B.A. from Northwestern University and a Ph.D. from Cornell University.
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1992-1996; I
  - Prudence Brown Chrons, 1992 January-June (Box 1)
  - Prudence Brown Chrons, 1992 July-October (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, 1992 October-December (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, 1993 January-March (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, 1993 April-June (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, 1993 July-September (Box 1)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, 1993 October-1994 March (Box 2)
  - Anne Kubisch Chrons, 1994 April-November (Box 2)
  - Janice Molnar Chrons, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Janice Molnar Chrons, 1994 December-1995 June (Box 2)
  - Janice Molnar Chrons, 1995 July-December (Box 2)
  - Janice Molnar Chrons, 1996 January-June (Box 2)
  - Janice Molnar Chrons, 1996 July-September (Box 2)
- Subject Files, 1984-1995; II
  - Urban Poverty Program Reviews 1, 1985-1992 (Box 3)
  - Urban Poverty Program Reviews 2, 1993-1995 (Box 3)
  - Urban Poverty Worldwide Staff Meeting (Cairo), 1993 February 19-21 (Box 3)
  - United Nations Conference on Women (1995) -- Planning Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program -- Assessment -- Grants Lists, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program -- Nairobi Meeting, 1985 July (Box 3)
  - Women's Program -- October 7, 1985 Meeting, 1985 October 7 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program Forum, 1986-1994 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program Forum -- Ford Foundation Annual Report, Nairobi Women's Conference RGA, Meetings Memoranda, etc., 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Women's Program Forum -- Ford Foundation Newsletter, 1989 March (Box 3)
  - Women's Program Forum Symposium -- Incl. "The Changing Context for Movements to Improve Women's Lives", 1986 September 29 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #1 -- Ford Foundation Work/Family, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #1 -- Survey, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #1, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #2, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #2 -- Survey Feedback -- Preliminary Draft, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Work and Family Task Force #3 -- Meetings, Notes, Report, etc., 1988-1990 (Box 4)